Zeljko Dakic

Senior Developer & Code Enthusiast

zeljko@gmail.com @desireco Github

Overview

I am an accomplished software engineer with more than 10 years of experience on high-profile projects, **looking for leadership role** to engineer project success.

Technology

Apply methodologies: Agile (Scrum and XP), Test Driven Development, System Analysis, Full Lifecycle

Development, Object-Oriented Design and Development

Languages: Ruby, Javascript, CoffeeScript, PHP, dabble in Elixir, ClojureScript etc

Internet Development: Rails, Node.js, Backbone, AngularJS, Meteor, Laravel

UI: ¡Query, Zurb Foundation, Bootstrap, Haml, Slim, UIKit...

Manage & Model Databases: MySQL, MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Neo4j, RethinkDB

Testing: RSpec, Cucumber, Factory Girl, Capybara, Selenium, Jasmine, Watir

Experience

Lead Developer, ParkWhiz, Chicago (Sep 2014-Current)

Coordinate work with consulting team and provide support and guidance Implement good practices like continous integration and code coverage Implement api using engines

Process: Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Cucumber, Agile

Lead Developer, Enova, Chicago (May 2014-Sep 2014)

Coordinate work with offshore team and provide support and guidance Work as developer on Canada and Australia team Improve test suite

Process: Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Cucumber, Agile

Lead Developer, FitStudio/Sears Holdings, Chicago (Dec 2011-Apr 2014)

Plan, develop and maintain fitstudio.com

Work as lead on searsstyle.com and part of kenmoreconnect.com team Coordinate work with offshore team and provide support and guidance **Process:** *Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Cucumber, Agile, Neo4j, MongoDB, Sass*

Senior Developer, BenchPrep, Chicago (Apr 2011-Sept 2011)

Work on BenchPrep main product, implemented discussion feature

Introduced integration testing using Cucumber/Selenium

Process: Ruby on Rails, Backbone, CoffeeScript, RSpec, Cucumber, Agile

Software Developer & Consultant, Obtiva/Groupon, Chicago (Jul 2010-Apr 2011)

Worked on key new features like merchant self service center

Internal tools, involved in performance tuning initiatives.

Created map visualisation of subscriber distribution for deal targeting

Process: Ruby on Rails, TDD, RSpec, Cucumber, Resque, Haml, Sass

Developer & Frontend Lead, Obtiva/ManageMyHome.com, Chicago (Jul 2009-Jun 2010)

ManageMyHome.com I was working on front-end and lead front end team in number of initiatives to bring standard based design, refactor and implement best practices

Process: Ruby on Rails, TDD, Scrum, RSpec, Cucumber, Selenium, Git, jQuery, Jasmine

Education

B.S., Business Administration (Management Information Systems) 2001

University of Belgrade, Serbia